In this video, we're going to look at
creating a payables transaction in
Dynamics GP and compare that to the
experience of entering the same payables
transaction in Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
In my GP system, I have created an AP
invoice for some office supplies that we
have purchased from one of our vendors.
I've entered in the vendor information,
the vendor invoice number, as well as
the purchase amount for the supplies.
Now, let's explore how we can enter that
same transaction in Business Central.
In Business Central, you can use the
purchase journal or purchase invoices to
register the cost of purchases and track
accounts payable. Purchase journals can
be used to register expenses for things
you may not track in inventory, while
purchase invoices can be used to track
purchases of
items as well as non-inventoried items.
To create AP transactions, we'll search
for purchase journals and choose the
purchase journal link in the search
results.
I can enter in the vendor invoice number
just as I did in GP and now select my
same vendor.
Next, I can enter in my purchase amount
and select my office supply GL account.
Before posting my transaction, I can see
a preview of the GL accounts the
transaction will be posted to.
This would be similar to clicking on the
distributions button in GP.
Now, let's look at entering in a
purchase invoice.
To create a purchase invoice,
we will go ahead and search for purchase
invoices
and select the link in the search
results.
Next, we can choose new to create the
invoice.
The first thing to do is choose the
vendor that we are purchasing those
supplies from. After selecting the
vendor, you can see the vendor
information has defaulted in from the
vendor record.
Next, we will record the vendor invoice
number.
Now, we can add the lines to the
purchase invoice. If we're wanting to
register purchases for services or items
not found in inventory, we can select
the GL account. And in this example,
select our supplies account.
Next, we can update the description if
necessary,
as well as enter in the purchase amount.
Because the purchase invoice is allowed
for multiple types, we could also enter
in lines for inventory items, fixed
assets, or track any freight freight
expenses we may have occurred.
Through the use of purchase journals and
purchase invoices, Business Central
provides additional flexibility when
capturing your business expenses.